YANNIC FRANCIS

class FlutterDeveloper extends StatefulWidget {...

Contact

Email

yannic.a.francis@gmail.com

Phone

404-436-9993

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yannic-francis-b1980718b/

Github

https://github.com/YannicAmir

Skills

Flutter, Dart, Provider, Git, GitHub, Mobile App Development, App Store, Play Store, RESTful APIs, JSON, Visual Studio Code, Firebase, Firebase Analytics, Mixpanel, Android Studio, State Management, UI/UX, SQL, Google Cloud Platform, TTD, DevOps, Widget/Unit/Integration Testing

Education

Master of Business Admin. Finance Clark Atlanta University Aug 2019 - Dec 2021 Atlanta, GA

Profiles

YouTube (Content Creator)

https://www.youtube.com/ channel/

<u>UCTCYBmVegORTaWCFuImP0Dw</u>

Medium (Writer)

https://medium.com/@yannicamir

UP 365 (Mobile App)

iPhone

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/ up-365/id1575621408

Android

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?

id=com.up365.up 365 finance

Professional Summary

I'm a Flutter developer with a formal education as an MBA in finance and 3 years of Flutter experience. I've led a small team through the full software development life cycle (SDLC) for iOS and Android: including planning, developing, releasing, and maintaining a complex mobile app in the App Store and Play Store.

Experience

Lead Flutter Developer (Sep 2022 - present)

Gervais Mechanical LLC / Infiniserv.pro

- Responsible for the full SDLC of Infiniserv.pro (mobile)
- Successfully published Infiniserv.pro to Apple's TestFlight and Google's internal testing
- Directed HVAC technicians and managers in getting Infiniserv.pro installed on their devices

Founder | Lead Flutter Developer (March 2020 - present)

UP 365 Limited Liability Company

- Conceptualized, planned, designed and created UP 365, a stock market mobile app for retail investors
- Created and maintained Apple and Google developer profiles
- Successfully published UP 365 in the App Store and Play Store
- Responsible for the design, build, deployment, debug & maintenance of UP 365 for Google Play and the App Store
- Tested UP 365 on multiple devices to ensure compatibility standards
- Hired and managed 2 employees and directed the development of UP 365's backend
- Oversaw the building of UP 365's database using a Google Cloud VM instance and SQL
- · Directed the migration of UP 365's database to Firebase
- Responsible for setting up and maintaining version control, using Git and Github
- Trained employees on Git version control
- Responsible for setting KPIs and implementing Firebase Analytics; this
 reflected UP 365's daily average engagement time of over 1 hour 30
 minutes and allowed the team to make data-based decisions
- Utilized RESTful APIs to retrieve and display data on over 10,000 companies featured on UP 365

Item Management Specialist (May 2018 - Aug 2019)

Robins Air Force Base

- Managed a \$20M portfolio of 60+ Special Operations assets using inventory tracking software
- Succeeded in updating database with documents from 1,000+ paper files
- Created Microsoft Excel spreadsheets to forecast repair needs for a portfolio of 10 mission-critical assets
- Consulted with Air Force leadership on ways to improve the Premiere College Internship Program (PCIP)—as a result, the second wave of PCIP Interns experienced more field rotations
- Mentored 3 Summer 2019 PCIP Interns



class FlutterDeveloper extends StatefulWidget {...

Influenced the hiring of 3 FVSU students